Guide to the Marvin Mirsky Papers 1941-2014
University of Chicago Library
Mirsky, Marvin. Papers
1941-2014
19.25 linear feet (36 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Marvin Mirsky (1923-1914) scholar of literature and longtime faculty member at the University of Chicago. The papers include course materials, notes, articles, and correspondence.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research, with the exception of Series VII. Series VII contains evaluative student materials that are closed for eighty years from their date of creation
Biographical Note
Marvin Mirsky was born in New York City on May 31, 1923. He worked as a code breaker in the State Department Intelligence Division during World War II. After the war, he was a Fulbright scholar in Paris, France.
Mirsky taught at the University of Chicago from 1962-1992, focusing on courses in literature and critical thinking in the humanities department of the College as well as in the Basic Program of Liberal Education for Adults in the Graham School. He was interested in how literature deals with ethical questions, which fueled his co-development of the course Human Being and Citizen, an interdisciplinary course that is still offered as part of first-year general education at the University. Mirsky’s love for teaching also extended beyond university classrooms. Until his death in May 2014, Mirsky held informal classes and private discussion groups for adults in the greater Chicago community, most of which focused on contemporary literature, cinema, and theater. Mirsky also led a number of literary and theatre themed study tours across Europe and Canada.
Marvin Mirsky died in Chicago on May 20, 2014.
Scope Note
The Marvin Mirsky Papers include notes on literature and cinema, course materials, articles, and documents from discussion groups and trips. The collection is divided into seven series.
Series I: Literature contains notes taken by Mirsky on a broad range of literature, including some plays. It also contains articles, book reviews, discussion points, and some course materials relating to specific texts and authors. Documents in this series date from 1950 to 2014 and are organized alphabetically by authors’ surnames.
Series II: Cinema consists of Mirsky’s notes, as well as collected articles and reviews pertaining to cinema and film. The series covers a range of genres and includes many well-known directors and popular films. The materials in this series date from 1990 to2011. It is organized alphabetically by directors’ surnames.
Series III: Course Materials contains documents pertaining to Mirsky’s teaching career. The series contains notes, reading lists, course proposals and schedules, correspondence with students and administrators, examination templates, and paper assignments. This series includes courses in English, Fine Arts, Humanities, and Literature, which are organized by topic. It also contains materials from courses on specific authors and literary themes. Series III also includes some course materials and correspondence not directly affiliated with the University of Chicago, including materials from Indiana University. The materials in Series III date from 1954-2014.
Series IV: Reading and Film Groups consists of materials from community discussion groups on literature and film led by Marvin Mirsky. It includes discussion notes, correspondence, mailing lists and member directories, reading lists, schedules, and articles. This series dates from 1964 to 2012. It is organized by group name.
Series V: Articles consists of assorted newspaper and magazine articles, as well as book reviews. They are organized by topic, and date from 1957 to 2011.
Series VI: Personal contains Marvin Mirsky’s personal papers, including correspondence, notes, paper drafts, and literary analysis papers written by Mirsky. This series also includes a handwritten poetry sketchbook. The materials in this series date from 1941 to 2013.
Series VII contains restricted student materials that are closed for eighty years from their date of creation. Restricted until 2048.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
Browse finding aids by topic.
University of Chicago. Department of English Language and Literature. Records
University of Chicago. University Extension. Records
Subject Headings
Mirsky, Marvin; University of Chicago. Division of the Humanities; Humanities -- Study and teaching -- United States
INVENTORY
- Series I: Literature
  - Abe, Kobe, Kangaroo Notebook, notes, articles, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adiga, Aravind, The White Tiger, notes, articles, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aeschylus, notes, articles, 1962-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aksyonov, Vassily, Generations of Winter, notes, articles, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allende, Isabel, The Stories of Eva Luna, notes, articles, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Amis, Martin, London Fields, notes, articles, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Amis, Martin, Time’s Arrow, notes, articles, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Anderson, Sherwood, Winesburg, Ohio, notes, articles, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Antunes, Antonio Lobo, The Return of the Caravels, notes, articles, 2002-2013 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Appelfeld, Aharon, Badenheim 1939, notes, articles, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Appelfeld, Aharon, The Iron Tracks, notes, articles, 1991-1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Atwood, Margaret, Alias Grace, notes, articles, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Atwood, Margaret, The Blind Assassin, notes, articles, 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Augustine, Confessions, notes, articles, course materials, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Austen, Jane, notes, articles, course materials, correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Balzac, Honore, notes, articles, course materials, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Banville, John, The Sea, notes, articles, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Barnes, Julian, Cross Channel, notes, articles, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Barnes, Julian, A History of the World in 10 ½ Chapters, notes, articles, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Barnes, Julian, The Lemon Table, notes articles, 2003-2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Barnes, Julian, Love, etc., notes, articles, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Barnes, Julian, The Sense of an Ending, notes, articles, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Barton, Emily, Brookland, notes, articles, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Beckett, Samuel, notes, articles, 1964-2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Begley, Louis, The Man Who Was Late, note, articles, correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bellow, Saul, notes, articles, 1959-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bellow, Saul, articles, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bellow, Saul, The Adventures of Augie March, notes, articles, 1967-2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bellow, Saul, Him with His Foot in His Mouth and Other Stories, notes, articles, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bellow, Saul, Humboldt’s Gift, notes, articles, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bellow, Saul, Ravelstein, notes, articles, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bellow, Saul, A Theft; The Dean’s December, notes, articles, 1982-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Berberova, Nina, notes, articles, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Berger, John, Lilac and Flag; Pig Earth, notes, articles, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bible, Biblical Themes in Modern Literature, notes, articles, reading list, 1968-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bible, The Bible As Literature, notes, articles, 1961-1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bible, The Bible As Literature, notes, articles, 1977-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bible, Exodus, notes, articles, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bible, Genesis, notes, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bible, New Testament, notes, articles, 1975-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bible, New Testament, notes, articles, reading list, 1979-1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bloom, Harold; Rosenberg, David, The Book of J, notes, articles,1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bolaño, Roberto, By Night in Chile, notes, articles, 2003-2009 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Borges, Jorge Luis, Ficciones, notes, articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bowles, Paul, The Sheltering Sky, notes, articles, 2003-2005 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Broch, Hermann, The Sleep Walkers, notes, articles, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Brodkey, Harold, Stories in an Almost Classical Mode, notes, articles, 1969-1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bronte, Charlotte, Jane Eyre, notes, articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Byatt, A.S., The Djinn in the Nightingale’s Eye, notes, articles, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Byatt, A. S., The Matisse Stories, notes, articles, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Camus, Albert, The First Man, notes, articles, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Camus, Albert, The Stranger, notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Carey, Peter, Parrot and Oliver in America, notes, articles, 2009-2013 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Carroll, Lewis, Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland; Through the Looking Glass, notes, articles, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Carter, Angela, Wise Children, notes, articles, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Carver, Raymond, notes, articles, 1976-1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cather, Willa, notes, articles, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cela, Camilo Jose, The Hive, notes, articles, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Celine, Louis-Ferdinand, Journey to the End of the Night, notes, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cervantes, Miguel, Don Quixote, notes, articles, course materials, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Chabon, Michael, The Amazing Adventures of Kavalier and Clay, notes, articles, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Chabon, Michael, The Yiddish Policemen’s Union, notes, articles, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Chaucer, Geoffrey, Canterbury Tales, notes, articles, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chaucer, Geoffrey, The Canterbury Tales: A Retelling by Peter Ackroyd, notes, course materials, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chekhov, Anton, notes, articles, course materials, 1991-1998 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chiari, M., “Symbolism,” article, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Claudel, Paul, article, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Coetzee, J.M. Diary of a Bad Year, notes, articles, 2002-2009 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Coetzee, J.M., Disgrace, notes, articles, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Coetzee, J.M., Elizabeth Costello, notes, articles, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Coetzee, J.M., The Master of Petersburg, notes, articles, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Conrad, Joseph, notes, articles, course materials, 1974-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Crace, Jim, Genesis, notes, articles, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cunningham, Michael, The Hours, notes, articles, 1998-2003 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Danticat, Edwidge, The Dew Breaker, notes, articles, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - DeLillo, Don, The Body Artist, notes, articles, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - DeLillo, Don, Falling Away, notes, articles, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - DeLillo, Don, Point Omega, articles, 2010-2011 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - DeLillo, Don, White Noise; Underworld; Cosmopolis, notes, articles, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Desai, Anita, Fasting, Feasting, notes, articles, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Desai, Kiran, The Inheritance of Loss, notes, articles, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Diaz, Junot, The Brief Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao, notes, articles, 2007-2010 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Dickens, Charles, The Mystery of Edwin Drood, notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Dickens, Charles, “Selected Works,” notes, 1970-1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Dickens, Charles, “Selected Works,” course material, notes, articles, 1980-1986 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Doctorow, E.L., Billy Bathgate, notes, articles, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Doctorow, E.L., The Book of Daniel, notes, articles, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Doctorow, E.L., City of God, notes, articles, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Doctorow, E.L., Lives of the Poets, notes, articles, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Doctorow, E.L., Loon Lake, notes, articles, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Doctorow, E.L., The March, article, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Doctorow, E.L., Ragtime, notes, articles, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Doctorow, E.L., The Waterworks, notes, articles, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Doctorow, E.L., World’s Fair, notes, articles, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Dos Passos, John, USA, notes, articles, 1988-2002 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Dostoyevsky, Fyodor, The Brothers Karamazov, notes, articles, 1963-2013 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Dostoyevsky, Fyodor, Crime and Punishment, notes, articles, course materials, 1955-1991 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Dostoyevsky, Fyodor, The Gambler; The Double, notes, articles, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Dostoyevsky, Fyodor, Notes from Underground; The Idiot, notes, articles, course materials, student mailing list, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Dostoyevsky, Fyodor, The Possessed; The Brothers Karamazov; notes, articles, course materials, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Dostoyevsky, Fyodor, notes, articles, course materials, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Doyle, Roddy, Paddy Clarke Ha Ha Ha, notes, articles, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Doyle, Roddy, The Woman Who Walked Into Doors, notes, articles,1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Eco, Umberto, The Mysterious Flame of Queen Loana, notes, articles, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Eggers, Dave, A Hologram for the King, notes, articles, 2012-2013 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Ellison, Ralph, Invisible Man, notes, articles, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Eliot, George, Middlemarch, notes, articles, 1991-1994 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Eliot, T.S., The Wasteland, notes, articles, 1973-1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Englander, Nathan, For the Relief of Unbearable Urges, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Englander, Nathan, The Ministry of Special Cases, notes, articles, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Englander, Nathan, What We Talk About When We Talk About Anne Frank, notes, articles, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Enright, Anne, The Gathering, notes, articles, 2007-2008 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Erdrich, Louise, The Antelope Wife, notes, articles, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Erdrich, Louise, The Bingo Palace, notes, articles, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Erdrich, Louise, Four Souls, notes, articles, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Erdrich, Louise, The Last Report on the Miracles at Little No Horse, notes, articles, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Erdrich, Louise, The Plague of Doves, notes, articles, 2002-2008 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Erdrich, Louise, Tales of Burning Love, notes, articles, 1994-1996 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Erdrich, Louise, Tracks, notes, articles, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Eugenides, Jeffrey, Middlesex, notes, articles, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Euripides, Orestes; Bacchae; Electra, notes, articles, 1957-1966 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Fallada, Hans, Every Man Dies Alone, notes, articles, 2009-2010 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Faulkner, William, The Bear, notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Faulkner, William, Go Down, Moses; As I Lay Dying; Absalom, Absalom!, notes, articles, 1955-1987 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Faulkner, William, Light In August, notes, 1985-1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Faulkner, William, The Sound and the Fury, notes, articles, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Faulkner, William, general materials, reading list, student roster, articles, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Faulkner, William, course materials, articles, notes, student mailing list, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Faulkner, William, “Selected Works” notes, articles, course materials, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Fielding, Henry, Joseph Andrews, notes, course materials, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Fitzgerald, Penelope, The Bookshop; The Blue Flower, notes, articles, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Flanagan, Richard, Gould’s Book of Fish, notes, articles, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Flaubert, Gustave, Bouvard and Pecuchet, notes, article, 1972-1983 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Flaubert, Gustave, Madame Bovary, notes, articles, study guide, 1972-1983 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Flaubert, Gustave, Sentimental Education, notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Flaubert, Gustave, Slammbo, notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Flaubert, Gustave, Three Tales, notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Flaubert, Gustave, notes, chronology, course material, 1972-1983 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Ford, Ford Madox, The Good Soldier, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Forster, E.M., A Passage to India, notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Foulds, Adam, The Quickening Maze, notes, articles, correspondence, 2004-2012 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Franzen, Jonathan, The Corrections, notes, articles, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Franzen, Jonathan, Freedom, notes, articles, 2010-2011 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Frazier, Charles, Cold Mountain, notes, articles, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Fuentes, Carlos, The Orange Tree, notes, articles, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Garcia Marquez, Gabriel, The General in His Labyrinth, notes, articles, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Garcia Marquez, Gabriel, Memories of My Melancholy Whores, notes, articles, 2003-2007 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Garcia Marquez, Gabriel, Of Love and Other Demons, notes, articles, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Garcia Marquez, Gabriel, One Hundred Years of Solitude, notes, articles, 1988-2001 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Garcia Marquez, Gabriel, Strange Pilgrims, notes, articles, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Gide, Andre, notes, articles, 1953-1969 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Goldstein, Rebecca, 36 Arguments for the Existence of God, notes, articles, 2009-2011 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Gordimer, Nadine, notes, articles, 1952-1971 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Gracq, Julien, A Dark Stranger, notes, articles, 2010-2011 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Grass, Gunter, Crabwalk, notes, articles, 2003-2004 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Grass, Gunter, The Tin Drum, notes, articles, 1999-2001 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Hale, Benjamin, The Evolution of Bruno, notes, articles, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Hamid, Mohsin, The Reluctant Fundamentalist, notes, articles, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Harding, Paul, Tinkers, notes, articles, 2009-2010 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Hazzard, Shirley, The Great Fire, notes, articles, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Heller, Joseph, Closing Time, notes, articles, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Heller, Joseph, God Knows; Good as Gold; Something Happened, notes, articles, 1974-1984 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, The Sun Also Rises, notes, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Hempel, Amy, The Collected Stories, notes, articles, 2006-2007 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Hoban, Russell, Turtle Diary, notes, articles, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Holland, Travis, The Archivist’s Story, notes, articles, 2009-2010 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Homer, notes, teaching materials and examinations, 1954-1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Homer, notes, articles, essay prompts, 1977-1988 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Hosseini, Khaled, The Kite Runner, notes, articles, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Houellebecq, Michel, The Elementary Particles, notes, articles, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Houellebecq, Michel, The Possibility of an Island, notes, articles, 2006-2007 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Ibsen, Henrik, Ghosts, notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Ionesco, Eugene, notes, 1965-1969 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Ishiguro, Kazuo, A Pale View of Hills, notes, articles, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Ishiguro, Kazuo, Never Let Me Go, notes, articles, 2004-2006 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Ishiguro, Kazuo, The Remains of the Day, notes, articles, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Ishiguro, Kazuo, When We Were Orphans, notes, articles, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Ivey, Eowyn, The Snow Child, notes, articles, student list, 2012-2014 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Jacobson, Howard, The Finkler Question, notes, articles, 2010-2011 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - James, Henry, The Portrait of a Lady, notes, articles, 1997-1999 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - James, Henry, The Wings of the Dove, notes, articles, film reviews, 1982-2000 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - James, Henry, Selected Novels, reading list, notes, articles, 1982-1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - James, Henry, Selected Short Works, notes, syllabus, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - James, Henry, Selected Works, notes, articles, 1982-1993 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Jelinek, Elfriede, The Piano Teacher, notes, articles, 2004-2007 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Jhabvala, Ruth Prawer, Poet and Dancer, notes, articles, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Jin, Ha, Waiting, notes, articles, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Johnson, Charles, Middle Passage, notes, articles, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Johnson, Adam, The Orphan Master’s Son, notes, articles, 2012-2014 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Jones, Edward P., The Known World, notes, articles, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Joyce, James, Ulysses, notes, articles, 1988-2000 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Joyce, James, Ulysses, notes, articles, reading list, 1955-1998 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Kafka, Franz, notes, articles, reading lists, lectures, 1953-2001 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Kawabata, Yasunari, The Dancing Girl of Izu, notes, articles, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Kawabata, Yasunari, Snow Country, notes, articles, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Kennedy, William, Very Old Bones, notes, articles, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Kertesz, Imre, Detective Story, notes, articles, 2008-2009 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Kertesz, Imre, Fateless, notes, articles, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Kertesz, Imre, Fiasco, notes, articles, 2011 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Kiarostami, Abbas, The Wind Will Carry Us, articles, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Kingsolver, Barbara, Flight Behavior, notes, articles, 2012-2014 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Kingsolver, Barbara, The Lacuna, notes, articles, 2009-2010 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Klima, Ivan, Waiting for the Dark, Waiting for the Light, notes, articles, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Kourouma, Ahmadou, Allah is not Obliged, notes, articles, 2007-2008 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Kundera, Milan, Identity, articles, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Kundera, Milan, Ignorance, notes, articles, 2002-2003 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Kundera, Milan, Immortality, notes, articles, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Kundera, Milan, The Unbearable Lightness of Being; The Book of Laughter and Forgetting, notes, articles, 1980-1985 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Kushner, Tony, Angels in America, notes, articles, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Lakiri, Jhumpa, Unaccustomed Earth, notes, articles, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Lawrence, D.H., Selected Works, notes, articles, 1957-1997 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Le Clezio, Jean-Marie Gustave, The Prospector, notes, articles, 1985-2009 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Lehrer, Jonah, Proust Was a Neuroscientist, articles, 2007-2008 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Levi, Primo, notes, articles, 1984-1988 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Lightman, Alan, Einstein’s Dreams, notes, articles, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Lispector, Clarice, The Hour of the Star, notes, articles, 2009-2010 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Lowry, Malcolm, Under the Volcano, notes, articles, 2004-2005 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Lucretius, De Rerum Natura, notes, articles, course materials, 2013-2014 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - MacLaverty, Bernard, Grace Notes, notes, articles, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Mahfouz, Naguib, Adrift on the Nile, notes, articles, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Mahfouz, Naguib, notes, articles, 1998-1992 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Mailer, Norman, The Castle in the Forest, notes, articles, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Mann, Thomas, Buddenbrooks, notes, articles, 1987-1996 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Mann, Thomas, Joseph and His Brothers, notes, articles, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Mann, Thomas, Six Early Stories, notes, article, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Mann, Thomas, Buddenbrooks to The Magic Mountain, notes, articles, course materials, 1962-2000 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Mann, Thomas, The Joseph Story, the Faust Legend, and the Confidence Man, notes, articles, 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 10)